We all share the same fate.
Mission: Impossible - Dead Reckoning Part One is a action, thriller,
adventure film directed by Christopher McQuarrie.
Ethan Hunt and his IMF team embark on their most dangerous mission yet: To track down a terrifying
new weapon that threatens all of humanity before it falls into the wrong hands.
With control of the future and the world's fate at stake and dark forces from
Ethan's past closing in, a deadly race around the globe begins.
Confronted by a mysterious, all-powerful enemy, Ethan must consider that nothing can
matter more than his mission—not even the lives of those he cares about most.
Ethan Hunt, played by Tom Cruise.
Grace, played by Hayley Atwell.
Luther Stickell, played by Ving Rhames.
Benji Dunn, played by Simon Pegg.
Ilsa Faust, played by Rebecca Ferguson.
The White Widow, played by Vanessa Kirby.
Mission: Impossible – Dead Reckoning Part One is a 2023 American action spy film directed
by Christopher McQuarrie from a screenplay he co-wrote with Erik Jendresen.
It is the sequel to Mission: Impossible – Fallout (2018) and the
seventh installment in the Mission: Impossible film series.
The ensemble cast includes Tom Cruise, Hayley Atwell, Ving Rhames, Simon Pegg, Rebecca Ferguson,
Vanessa Kirby, Esai Morales, Pom Klementieff, Mariela Garriga and Henry Czerny.
In the film, Impossible Missions Force agent Ethan Hunt (Cruise) and his team face
off against the Entity, a powerful rogue artificial intelligence.
In January 2019, Cruise announced the next two Mission: Impossible films would
be shot back-to-back, with McQuarrie writing and directing both.
Returning and new cast members were announced soon after, and Lorne
Balfe, who composed the score for Fallout, returned to score.
Filming began in Italy in February 2020 but was halted by the COVID-19 pandemic.
It resumed later that year and wrapped in September 2021, with other filming
locations including Norway, the United Kingdom and the United Arab Emirates.
With an estimated gross budget of $291 million, including a net $220
million budget, it is one of the most expensive films ever made.
Mission: Impossible – Dead Reckoning Part One premiered in Rome on June 19, 2023, and was
theatrically released in the United States on July 12, by Paramount Pictures.
The film received critical acclaim and grossed $571.1 million worldwide, becoming the
tenth-highest-grossing film of 2023, but was still considered to be a box-office disappointment.
It was nominated in two categories at the 96th Academy
Awards and the 77th British Academy Film Awards.
A direct sequel, Mission: Impossible – The Final
Reckoning, was released in May 2025.
The film explores themes of mask, race against
time, mission, rome, italy, chase.
The tone is dark and intense.